The orb that I cast upon the
world transformed into a boy.
（観察者）
私が地上へ投げ入れた球(きゅう)は
少年に姿を変え
March, a girl from Ninannah, named him Fushi.
ニナンナの少女マーチによって
フシと名付けられた
Through the stimulation of
his battle against Oniguma,
オニグマとの戦いを通じ
フシは新たな刺激によって
Fushi acquired new information.
情報を獲得した
Thank you.
（フシ）あ… りがとオ
♪～
～♪
Listen, no one can see us playing this game.
（ペンナ）いい？
これは 人に
見つかっちゃいけないゲームよ
You have to hide here
until I come back. Okay?
次に私が来るまで
パロナは ここに隠れているの
分かった？
Onee-chan?
（パロナ）おねーちゃん？
Here's some food.
（ペンナ）食料よ
You can eat some berries if you run out.
なくなったら
木の実を取って食べて
Onee-chan!
あっ おねーちゃん！
I'll make you a new stuffed
doll when you win the game.
（ペンナ）ゲームをクリアしたら
また新しい ぬいぐるみ
作ってあげる
Parona!
Where have you been all week?
（村の女性）パロナ！
あんた１週間も どこ行ってたの？
Where's Onee-chan?
おねーちゃんは？
She's not here anymore.
（女性）ここには もういないよ
She was chosen to be the
sacrifice to Oniguma-sama.
オニグマ様への
ささげ物に選ばれたんだ
え？
あ…
Onee-chan!
おねーちゃん！
What a coward, running away from the ritual!
（男性）儀式から
逃げるとは―
Onee-chan!
情けないヤツだ
（パロナ）おねーちゃん！
And you call yourself a woman of Ninannah?
（男性）それでもニナンナの女か！
Onee-chan!
（パロナ）おねーちゃん！
You aren't of this village anymore!
（男性）お前は もう
ここの人間ではない！
Get out of here!
どこかへ行ってしまえ
（パロナ）
ハァハァ… あっ
あっ！
（パロナ）ハッ
I was dreaming.
夢か
I wonder what kind of
face she made back then.
あのとき お姉ちゃんは
どんな顔をしていたんだろう
A Large Vessel
（馬車の音）
Thank you.
（フシ）ありが… とオ
ありがとオ
（マーチ）キャハハ…
ヘンなワンちゃん！
Funny puppy!
ヘヘッ はい！
Here you go.
Thank you.
How much further are we going?
（フシ）ありがとオ
（パロナ）あと どれくらい
進むんだろうか？
（マーチ）キャハハ
It'll take another twenty
days to get to Yanome.
（ピオラン）
ここからヤノメの国まで
20日は かかるかのう
You're a Yanome shaman, aren't you?
あなたはヤノメの
祈祷(きとう)師さまですよね？
Why are you with us in this wagon?
なぜ私たちと同じ荷車に？
あ！
Oh, yeah!
そうよ！　マーチに
ひどいことした人だわ
She's the one who did horrible things to me!
Why did you choose me?!
なんでマーチを選んだのよ！
Because you were the prettiest.
あんたが一番
美人だったからじゃよ
R-Really?
そ… そう？
Look. I'm a criminal.
（ピオラン）ほれ…
（パロナ）あ！
わしは罪人じゃ
They're so desperate to satisfy their greed that
they get a fake shaman to help them murder.
エセ祈祷師で
人殺しの手伝いをするほど
ヤツらは欲を満たすのに必死なのさ
Greed?
Yanome wants Ninannah's lush lands.
欲？
ヤノメはニナンナの
豊かな大地が欲しい
That's why they became involved
with the sacrifice tradition.
そのために
伝統である いけにえの儀式に
首を突っ込んだのさ
They help with the ritual and show
their gratitude by providing supplies.
儀式を手伝い
お礼の物資を送り 感謝してみせる
"People of Ninannah, thank you for
protecting all of humanity from Oniguma."
ニナンナの人々よ
よくぞ地上の すべての民のため
オニグマから守ってくれたと
All that remains is psychological
manipulation and occupation.
その先にあるのは精神的な支配
そして侵略さ
I had no idea.
知りませんでした
（マーチの笑い声）
I'm disgusted that horrible ritual has been
carried on under the pretense of tradition.
あの恐ろしい儀式が
伝統の ひと言で片づけられ
ずっと おこなわれてきたことを
忌まわしく思います
Oh, my.
なんと…
I thought the people of Ninannah
were faithful to their beliefs,
たとえ同胞が死んでも
信仰に忠実なのが
ニナンナ人だと思っていたが…
even if it meant the deaths of their own.
Only the old grown-ups.
古い大人たちだけです
They don't care about what
those suffering endure.
ヤツらは
苦しんでいる者の心には無関心
We need to end this terrible
custom immediately.
このような悪い風習は
一刻も早く断つべきだ
That won't happen.
無理な話じゃ
Ninannah's elders are old-fashioned.
ニナンナの年寄りは封建的
They wouldn't believe you if you
told them that their god is dead.
“神は死んだ”と言ったところで
信じはしないだろうよ
God?
神…
What can we do?
一体 どうすれば…
（水しぶきの音）
（マーチ）あっ あっ ああ！
ダメダメ
No! No!
What's wrong?!
どうした？
It's so stinky!
（マーチ･パロナ）ああっ
べちょべちょクサーイ
（ピオランの笑い声）
It's coming this way!
こっちに流れてきた！
（パロナの悲鳴）
（マーチ）ああっ ヤダ！
Puppy!
ワンちゃーん 体洗おう
Let's wash ourselves off.
It's cold, but don't be afraid.
冷たいけど勇気を出して
（フシの鳴き声）
Remember...
（少年）僕のこと ずっと…
me...
forever.
覚えていて
（マーチ）あ…
My!
（ピオラン）なんと！
（パロナ･マーチ）あっ
So it was you!
あなただったのね！
I missed you!
エヘッ 会いたかったわ
You know him?
知ってるのか そいつのこと？
Yeah.
His name's Fushi-chan.
うん フシちゃんっていうの
We need to go before it gets dark.
（ハヤセ）
日が暮れるので行きますよ
No, Fushi-chan!
ああ… フシちゃん め！
Come with me.
マーチと一緒に来なさい
Good boy.
ヘヘ… はい お利口さん
I'll have to teach you how
to use the potty later, too.
あとで おトイレも覚えましょうね
Has he warmed up to March?
あれはマーチに なついてるのか？
Fu-chan's still a little boy.
フーちゃん まだ全然 子供なの
So I decided I'm going to be his mommy.
だからね マーチ
この子のママになることにしたの
"Fushi," as in "immortal," huh?
（ピオラン）
ほう… 不死身だからフシか
It's unfortunate for him
that he can't die, though.
しかし死ねないなんて―
不幸だな
（マーチ･ピオラン）え？
I think it matters to humans
what we spend our lives doing.
人間 命の使いどころというものが
ある気がする
What purpose are you supposed to
find in life if you live forever?
もしも命が無限なら
生きることに どんな意味を
見いだせばいいんだ？
Purpose?
いみ？
あ… ごめん
Sorry.
It's wrong of me to seek purpose
in another's life and death.
人の生き死にに
意味を求めるなんて間違ってる
I don't get it, but I'm
really happy right now.
よく分かんないけど
マーチは今とってもハッピーよ
Please wear these.
（ハヤセ）
どうぞ これを着てください
Are these Yanome clothes?
（パロナ）ヤノメの服か
There's a set for Fu-chan, too.
フーちゃんのも あるわね
I'll get you changed.
着せてあげる はーい バンザイ
Arms up!
What happens to us now?
私たちは これから　どうなる？
As of today,
今日から あなた方は…
you are March and Parona
of the nation of Yanome.
ヤノメ国のマーチとパロナです
Wow, look! Look!
（マーチ）
わっ わっ 見て ねーね！
All that yummy-looking food!
おいしそうなの たくさん！
So many pretty things!
きれいなのも いっぱい！
Help yourselves to whatever
you'd like to have.
（マーチの歓声）
好きなものを何でも
食べてください
I'll pay for it.
（マーチの歓声）
お金は私が払います
Really?
ホントに？
ん？　んー いいニオイ
It smells so good.
ヘヘッ あーん…
（店主）ああ！
（マーチ）ん…
Is there anything you'd like
to say to those you love?
（手紙屋）大切な人へ
伝えたい言葉はありませんか？
え？
Letters! Letters!
（手紙屋）
手紙屋！　手紙屋だよ
Hey! Hey! Over there!
We deliver your messages!
（マーチ）ねーね あれ！
あなたの言葉 届けるよ
（パロナ）え？
Welcome.
らっしゃい
Write what you want to say or convey here.
言いたいこと 伝えたいことを
これに書いて
え？　かく？
Write?
Oh, I see.
（手紙屋）ああ そうか 心配ないよ
Not to worry.
I'll write for you. Go ahead and tell me.
俺が代わりに書くから
言ってごらん
Let's see...
えっとね…
Mommy, Daddy, how are you?
“パパ ママ 元気？”
I'm in Yanome right now.
“マーチは今ヤノメにいるわ”
Don't worry about me.
“心配しないで”
The end.
終わり
Okay.
オーケー
And where shall I deliver it to?
で どこに届けます？
To Mommy and Daddy.
パパとママに ニナンナにいるの
They're in Ninannah.
Ninannah?!
ニナンナ？
The sacred land of Oniguma-sama?!
オニグマ様の聖地の
あのニナンナかい？
That's right.
そうよ
Ninannah has no reading or writing.
ニナンナには
文字の文化はありません
Neither your father nor your mother will
understand what's written in the letter.
その手紙に書かれた文字
マーチさんの お父さまも
お母さまも理解できませんよ
え？
I know a different kind of writing, though.
でもマーチ 別の文字 知ってるし
Oh? What does it look like?
ほう… どんなものです？
ええっ
えーい…
Like this!
これよ！
What does that say?
それ 何と書いてあるのです？
（マーチ）フンッ
It says, "March is doing great!"
“マーチは元気よ”って意味よ
March...
Send this, please.
マーチ…
これを送ってちょうだい
Sure.
ああ ニナンナの どの地域だい？
Where in Ninannah?
I said, to Mommy and Daddy!
だからパパとママの所よ
Which district? Which street?
何番地区の何丁目？　管轄は誰？
Whose jurisdiction?
ああ…
Sissy, do you know?
（マーチ）ねーね 知ってる？
（パロナ）いや…
No.
Ninannah is large.
ニナンナは広い
The nearest district alone has 40 settlements.
一番近い地区でも
40も集落があるけど…
What is that drawing?
何ですか その絵？
ああ…
March-san, let's have dinner.
マーチさん 夕食にしましょう
ああ… ん…
I'll hold on to this letter for you.
この手紙 預かっておくよ
Let's come back when we find out
where Mommy and Daddy live.
パパとママの住所が分かったら
また来よう
Fine.
（マーチ）分かったわ
（料理を貪る声）
What is this?
（マーチ）
何これ？　しゅごくウマい
It's so good!
Look at how she eats.
ねえ 見て あの食べ方
（２人の笑い声）
Thank you.
ありがとオ ありがとオ…
Now, Fushi-chan, mind your manners.
（マーチ）こらこら フシちゃん
お行儀よくしなきゃダメでしょ
Remember what I told you?
前も言ったじゃない
You have to eat with your hands, like this.
こう 手に取って食べるの
Got it?
分かった？
March-san, why don't you mind your manners
and use the chopsticks on your head, too?
マーチさんも お行儀よく
その頭の箸で食べたら
いかがですか？
Chopsticks?
はし？
These are head scratchers.
これは“頭かゆいかゆい棒”でしょ
You use them when your head's itchy.
頭が かゆいときに使うもので…
フッ ニナンナには
It seems that Yanome's culture hasn't
been correctly conveyed to Ninannah.
我々ヤノメの文化が
間違って伝わったようですね
I apologize.
失礼しました
そのままで構いませんよ
Please continue as you were.
Eat however you like, Fushi-chan.
フシちゃん 好きに食べなさい
ん！
Are you okay, Fushi-chan?
（マーチ）
わわっ 大丈夫 フシちゃん？
（フシ）ぐっ ううう…
ああ！
It seems he's learned the
Yanome way of eating.
（ハヤセ）覚えたようですね
ヤノメの食べ方を
Well, March-san?
どうです マーチさん？
Yanome is a fine nation, don't you think?
ヤノメ国は いい所でしょう？
Don't you think it's a plenty comfortable
place to spend the rest of your life?
一生 暮らすには
十分 住みよいと思いませんか？
I don't really...
別に マーチは…
ん？　マーチ？
March?
How unfortunate.
フッ 残念です
（フシ）ううう…
The western morning glory is indeed effective.
やはりニシアサガオは
よく効きますね
As I said before, for the first time
in the long history of the ritual,
（ハヤセ）
先に お伝えしたとおり
我々は長きにわたって
おこなってきた儀式で
we have finally seen Oniguma-sama
for the first time, and captured it.
ついに初めてオニグマ様を目にし
保護いたしました
There's also something I'd like to show you.
それに加え 今回
お見せしたいものがあります
That boy.
あの少年です
As we were about to leave following the ritual,
儀式をおこなった帰り道
we witnessed the boy defeat Oniguma-sama.
我々は オニグマ様を
少年が打ち破る姿を目撃しました
That boy? Defeated Oniguma?
（重鎮）あの少年がオニグマを？
Yes.
He is immortal.
はい 彼は不死身です
（格子が開く音）
Go.
（従者）行け！
If I kill you, I get to walk free!
（罪人）お前を殺せば無罪放免だ！
うわああ！
くっ えい…
フフフ… え？
His wound!
傷口が… ウソだろ！
That's impossible!
うわーっ
ギャ…
It hurts! It hurts! It hurts!
痛い痛い… 痛い！
It hurts! It hurts!
ああ 痛い…
It hurts.
イタイ イタイ…
It hurts! It hurts! It hurts!
It hurts.
痛い… 痛い！
イタイ イタイ
It hurts! It hurts!
痛い 痛い 痛い…
It hurts.
（ピオランの叫び声）
Forgive me, boy!
許せ 小僧！
I wanna get out, find a lover,
eat good food, and have some fun!
外へ出て 恋人と会って
ウマいもん食って楽しみたいんじゃ
It hurts.
So die, please!
だから死んでくれ！
（フシ）イタイ イタイ
It hurts.
（ピオランの叫び声）
イタイ イタイ
It hurts.
Is he a god or a monster?
（重鎮）
彼は神なのか？　魔物なのか？
（ピオランの叫び声）
I don't know.
It hurts.
（ハヤセ）さあ…
しかし私は こう思います
I believe, though...
（フシ）イタイ イタイ
It hurts.
that his power is unlimited.
彼の力は未知数ですが
He is essential to Yanome's future.
ヤノメの未来には
必要な人物であると
Move it, old hag!
（従者）どけ バアさん！
I'll lop your head off!
お前の首を斬る！
（従者）おお…
（従者）えっ
（従者たちの悲鳴）
（フシの鳴き声）
あ…
（鍵を開ける音）
（扉が開く音）
It hurts.
（フシ）イタイ…
（マーチ）あっ フーちゃん！
Fu-chan!
It hurts.
March-san, please make sure he behaves.
マーチさん そいつを
おとなしくさせておいてください
It hurts.
（フシ）イタ… イ
Be strong.
我慢して
It hurts.
（フシ）イタイ イタイ…
（マーチ）ふっ
They won't get away with this.
許せないわ こんなことして…
There, there.
よしよーし
よしよーし よしよーし…
There, there.
There! All better!
よし 治った！
You did good, Fu-chan.
よく がんばったわね フーちゃん
March, is Fushi with you?
（パロナ）
マーチ？　フシと一緒か？
Sissy?
ねーね！　どこにいるの？
Where are you?
うーん…
（水が流れる音）
Over here, March.
（パロナ）こっちだ マーチ
Sissy!
ねーね！
What's in your room?
そっちの部屋には何がある？
Straw, a pot... and this. That's it.
ワラとツボと あ…
これだけよ
Okay.
Tie that to this.
（パロナ）
よし！　これに くくってくれ
Where are we?
ここは どこなの？
What's going to happen to us?
マーチたち どうなるの？
Don't worry, March.
心配ないよ マーチ
I know.
Could you gather some of Fushi's fur?
そうだ フシの毛を
集めてくれないか？
Fu-chan's?
フーちゃんの？
To the right.
（従者）もっと右！　そのまま
Keep going.
（マーチ）あ…
Mister!
おじさん！
When do we get to leave?
マーチたちは いつ出られるの？
You're staying here forever.
（従者）一生ここだ
え！
It hurts. It hurts.
（フシ）イタイ イタ…
It hurts. It hurts. It hurts.
イタイ イタイ イタイ…
ん？
What's wrong?
どうしたの？
ケガは もう治ったでしょ？
Your wound's all better, isn't it?
It hurts.
It hurts. It hurts.
（フシ）イタイ イタイ…
Fu-chan?
ん？　フーちゃん？
It hurts.
（フシ）イタイ イタイ…
（フシのうなり声）
It hurts.
（フシ）イタイ…
It hurts. It hurts.
イイ… イタイ イタイ…
It hurts.
ん？
（フシ）イタイ…
What is this?
（マーチ）何かしら？
ぬぬぬ… んー
It hurts.
イタイ…
あっ
ああ… 矢？
An arrow?
These are all arrows?
あっ こんなに いっぱい！
Poor thing.
かわいそうに… 治してあげないと
We have to make him better.
How is our progress?
（ハヤセ）進捗は どうだ？
No one seems to want to
tend to Oniguma-sama.
（従者）それが誰もオニグマ様の
世話をしたがらなくて…
How could it be so difficult
to take care of a bear?
（ハヤセ）クマの世話の何が
一体 難しいのか
あ…
Let's have her do it.
この子にさせましょう
（フシのうなり声）
Are you sure? It's dangerous.
（従者）
いいんですか？　危険ですよ
It's fine.
構いません
She's just a little girl.
It won't matter if she dies.
ただの娘が死んだところで
問題はないでしょう
I can't believe she's making
you take care of that bear.
（パロナ）まさか あのクマの
世話を任せられるとはな
It's too dangerous to do it yourself.
１人じゃ危険すぎるぞ
I have Fushi-chan and Kanitaro with me.
フシちゃんとカニ太郎が
一緒だから大丈夫よ
I'll be all right.
You're doing cleaning, right, Sissy?
それより ねーねは
お掃除のお仕事するんでしょ？
Hang in there.
がんばって
Yeah.
（パロナ）ああ でも…
But...
Don't worry.
大丈夫よ
First, I'm going to pretend to be
Yanome with that old lady's help.
（パロナ）まずは―
あのおばあさんと協力して
ヤノメに化ける
ぐええ… たちけてくれーい！
Help me!
I'm dying!
死ぬー！
And then we'll help you.
（パロナ）そしてマーチを助ける
We did it!
（マーチ）やったわ！
（ピオラン）逃げろ
We'll kill Oniguma, and we'll bring
home its hide and eyes as proof.
（パロナ）オニグマを殺し
その証しとして
目と皮を切り取り 持ち帰る
Then I'm sure the people
of Ninannah will agree
それを見せればニナンナの
みんなも納得するはずだ
that we don't need that ritual anymore!
もう あの儀式は必要ないと
I think we can do it.
これなら やれそうだ
No, we have to.
いや やるんだ 何としても
No matter what.
Right, Onee-chan?
だよね お姉ちゃん…
You're just like me, huh?
（マーチ）あなたって私と一緒よね
People said I was special and
amazing when I left Ninannah.
マーチもニナンナを出るときは
みんなから“すごい”とか
“特別だ”とか言われたけど
I'm just a little girl, though.
ただの女の子なのよね
It hurts.
（フシ）イタイ イタイ
And you're just a bear that likes human meat.
あなたは人間のお肉が好きな
ただのクマさん
People made a fuss about you,
and they shot you with arrows...
It hurts.
いろんな人に騒がれて
矢で刺されて
（フシ）イタイ イタイ
It hurts.
And you really ended up
looking like Oniguma-sama.
It hurts.
本当にオニグマ様みたいに
なっちゃった
（フシ）イタイ イタイ
It hurts.
You'll be able to go home
once your wounds heal.
ケガが治ったら きっと帰れるわ
You can go home.
帰れる… うっ
I'm sorry I made you feel uneasy.
あ… ごめんね 不安にさせちゃって
I'm sorry.
ごめんね
There, there.
よしよし よしよし…
よしよし…
It hurts.
（フシ）イタイ イタイ…
Thank you.
あ… りがとオ
え？
あっ
The vessel opened.
（観察者）器は空いた
（強風の音）
フゥ フゥ…
んっ くっ…
Oniguma is dead.
オニグマは死んだ
They'll come retrieve the body by tomorrow.
明日になれば回収される
We need to escape with the proof first.
その前に“証し”を手にして
脱出するんだ
We'll be out of here in no time, March.
マーチ すぐに出られるからな
You don't need to become a
grown-up in this damn place.
こんな所で
大人にならなくていいんだ
あ… ハッ
んっ
うわあ…
うっ く…
あ… あ… んっ
ハッ
あっ あそこなら…
Over there!
ふっ
Onee-chan!
お姉ちゃん！
It hurts.
（フシ）イ… タイ
ん？　あ…
Looks like I'm in a storage room.
（パロナ）ここは…
用具置き場か
ハッ
Look who it is.
（従者）何かと思ったら お前か
It's you.
I won't tell anyone that
you tried to run away.
脱走しようとしてたことは
黙っててやるから
So just do as I say.
おとなしくしてな
ヘヘッ
おわっ…
（パロナ）ふんっ
（従者）ぐあ…
How dare you?!
（従者）やりやがったな… うっ
ひえっ…
I won't tell anyone.
（パロナ）黙っててやる
おとなしくしていろ！
So do as I say.
Shift's up.
（従者）交代だ
（足音）
（マーチ）あ…
You!
（従者）おい！
え？　何… ですか？
What do you want?
I'm taking you with me.
（従者）お前を連行する
え！
フッ
Onee-chan, I bet you were
smiling, too, weren't you?
お姉ちゃん
あなたも きっと笑ってた
そうでしょ？
So I'm going to make good use
of the life you gave me.
だから私も お姉ちゃんに
もらった命 ちゃんと使うよ
We're escaping.
脱出だ
Sissy!
ねーね！
♪～
～♪
Preview
Parona and the others leave the prison,
carrying out their plan to return to Ninannah.
（観察者）
ニナンナに戻る計画を決行し
監獄を出るパロナたち
But a party of Yanome led by Hayase
mercilessly blocks their way.
しかしハヤセ率いるヤノメの一団が
容赦なく その行く手を阻む
With their grand escape, yet another
change comes upon Fushi's body.
壮絶な逃避行の果て
フシの体には
また１つ新しい変化が起こる
Those Who Follow